JEREMY BENSOUSSAN

+972 54 344 1935 | jeremy@bensous.net | Raanana

SUMMARY

Data Science student, I am specializing in deep learning and natural language processing. My goal is to join a successful AI research and development team within the Israeli hi-tech scene. Prior to that I have 12 years of experience as a project manager and team leader in capital markets quantitative development. I have a track-record of implementing state-of-the-art data analysis and decision-making applications for one of the world's most successful investment companies.

EDUCATION

2018 – 2019	Data Science Professional Course – Israel Tech Challenge – <i>Tel Aviv</i> Five-months full-time training course qualifying M.Sc. and PhD graduates as professional Data Scientists. Main focus in Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision and NLP
2005 – 2006	Advanced Master in Computer Science and Finance – SKEMA – <i>Sophia-Antipolis</i> Financial Markets, Innovation & Technology
2004 – 2005	Postgraduate Degree in Business – American University – <i>Washington DC / Paris</i> International exchange program with Dauphine – Major in Finance
2000 – 2004	M.Sc. in Computer Science – Dauphine University – Paris Master of Business Informatics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2011 – 2018	3	Breva

Brevan Howard / Hedge Fund – Quantitative Developer – *Ramat Gan*

- Project lead on the main risk & profit / loss analysis app for equity derivatives (50+ users)
 Implemented a trading opportunity research model based on volatility time-series analysis
- Cleaned and processed real-time and static data from various sources: market streams, databases, time-series, third party datasets ...
- Built daily reports for the CIO of the company

2010 - 2011

1 year

7 years

Royal Bank of Canada – Project manager – London

- Developed end of day curve fitting process for interest rates, bonds and FX spot/forwards
- Improved data consistency across different revaluation engines

2007 – 2010

3 vears

Bank Société Générale - Team Leader - Trading Floor Tactical IT team - London

- Led a team of 5 people implementing and supporting trading floor applications
- Developed the main risk & profit / loss applications for emerging markets traders (70+ users)
- Coordinated the development and support of 30+ projects: market contribution, data analysis, statistical analysis, trading opportunities

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Science Programming/DB Deep learning, sequence modelling, unsupervised learning, regression and classification models

Python, java, SQL, VBA

Frameworks/Libs Spa

Spark, sklearn, spaCy, nltk, tensorflow, keras, bokeh

Other AWS, Expert Excel skills, git, Linux, quantitative finance, Reuters, Bloomberg

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages
Talmudic Studies
Mobile apps

English: fluent – Hebrew: intermediate (ulpan level dalet) – French: native

Tractate Berachot, Baba Metsia, Shabbat, Ketubot, Kiddushin

Shabbat Alert (iOS) – 90 000+ downloads – average rating: $\star \star \star \star \star \frac{1}{2}$

Fencing Maccabiah Games team series – 2001 Gold medal – 2007 (European games) Gold medal

French Championship team series – Silver medal in 2001, Bronze medal in 1999

References available upon request